<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iPad | Matt Morris]]></title>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/categories/ipad/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-04T16:02:26-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mmorris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Rainbows Attack]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/03/26/colors-that-lie/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T11:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/03/26/colors-that-lie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading some of the <a href="http://www.marco.org/2012/03/20/consumer-reports-sensationalism">recent commentary</a> regarding Consumer Reports' sensationalistic report of the New iPad&rsquo;s running temperature, I  would like to also point out the problems that come with using a rainbow color map in a visualization such as this.</p>

<p>A color map is simply a look-up table that maps a range of values into a range of colors. Color maps are frequently used in medical and other scientific visualizations to achieve expressive visualizations. A carefully chosen color map can reveal important characteristics of the data under investigation. But a poor color map can actually introduce artifacts into the final image.</p>

<p>Consumer Reports has chosen the canonical bad color map.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Rainbows, Rainbows Everywhere</h2>

<p>They have chosen a rainbow color map to visualize the surface temperature on the New iPad. Loosely speaking, a rainbow color map traverses all the &ldquo;colors of the rainbow.&rdquo; For example, given a data set with values between 0 and 255, a rainbow map migh map the colors as follows: 0:blue, 100:green, 200:yellow, 255:red. Then the final image is rendered by taking the data values and drawing color pixels on the screen using the map. The problem with this is that the human eye perceives the transitions between the different colors as discrete events. This image, for example, maps values 0 to 300 using a rainbow map that I created in Pixelmator.</p>

<center><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/6872106300/" title="rainbow by Matt Morris, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6037/6872106300_a3d0f5a9c2.jpg" width="80" height="300" title="'rainbow'" ></a></center>


<p>See the transition between red and yellow? Surely there is something significant in the data going on there, right? Right??</p>

<p><strong>No</strong>. That &ldquo;line&rdquo; between the red and yellow is created in the eye and mind of the viewer and is due to the way that I constructed the color map. Here is the same [0,300] data rendered with a saturation based map.</p>

<center><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/7018214653/" title="red by Matt Morris, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7249/7018214653_0e314d757b.jpg" width="80" height="300" title="'red'" ></a></center>


<p>Imagine if the underlying data were temperature values. This would make it appear that there are sudden temperature changes at certain locations, when in fact the temperature change is very smooth. And it certainly makes a more dramatic image if you map the higher temperatures to the red/orange colors, yes?</p>

<p>If you give me a dataset and enough time to play with the color transform, I can make all kinds of crazy features emerge in the image.</p>

<p>To their credit, Consumer Reports does, at least, appaer to use the same color map for both visualizations. However, it seems very convient that the &ldquo;cooler&rdquo; iPad is colored with mostly blue hues, which fits the narrative very nicely.</p>

<p>There is a mountain of visualization research that explains why rainbow color maps are horrible. To get the complete story, I recommend <a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/freeabs_all.jsp?arnumber=4118486"><strong>Rainbow Color Maps (Still) Considered Harmful</strong></a> by Borland and Taylor. I think this quote explains the situation pretty well.
<blockquote><p>Not only does the rainbow color map confuse viewers through its lack of perceptual ordering and obscure data through its inability to present small details, but it actively misleads the viewer by introducing artifacts to the visualization. The rainbow color map appears as if it’s separated into bands of almost constant hue, with sharp transitions between hues. Viewers perceive these sharp transitions as sharp transitions in the data, even when this is not the case.</p><footer><strong>&lsquo;Borland and Taylor&rsquo; <a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/freeabs_all.jsp?arnumber=4118486">http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/freeabs_all.jsp?arnumber=4118486</a> &lsquo;Rainbow Color Map (Still) Considered Harmful&rsquo;</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>I hesitate to rehost or hotlink this document, because I think IEEE is still charging for this kind of research, but if you Google for the title, you&rsquo;ll find it hosted on CS department webservers all over the country. Check out their &ldquo;works cited&rdquo; for further reading.</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/boxel">Leave a Response</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
