<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></title>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-18T17:52:42-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mmorris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Playing Around with the Fitbit API]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2014/01/18/playing-around-with-the-fitbit-api/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-18T17:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2014/01/18/playing-around-with-the-fitbit-api</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently became interested in pulling some of my own personal data from the <a href="http://dev.fitbit.com/">Fitbit API</a>. I&rsquo;ve never used OAuth before, and it&rsquo;s been years since I last made any serious use of python, but I managed to throw together a small program that does a few basic things. Currently it just posts your cumulative year to date total floors climbed to Twitter. Feel free to have a look at the <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/FitTweets">github project</a>.</p>

<p>It was right about when I got this far with the project that I realized that there is <a href="http://blog.app.net/2013/11/12/a-simple-way-to-get-started-with-the-app-net-api/">now a free way</a> to play around with the <a href="http://developers.app.net/">App.net API</a>. So I&rsquo;ll be adding ADN support and make it into a more interesting bot.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back to Octopress Master]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/08/18/back-to-octopress-master/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-18T20:58:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/08/18/back-to-octopress-master</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After playing with the <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/blogging/linklog/">link log</a> feature in the Octopress 2.1, and now <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/tree/3.0">3.0</a>, branches, I&rsquo;ve decided to come back to the master branch. Octopress 3.0 looks like it&rsquo;s going to be very nice, but things are too unstable for me at the moment. I shouldn&rsquo;t be spending so much time hacking on the site itself when there is actual work to do.</p>

<p>For the linklog posts I&rsquo;ve already made, I just edited the entry with a link to the external URL in the body of the post. Apologies if this causes repeat entries to appear in your RSS feed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working from Home]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/07/21/working-from-home/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-21T21:16:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/07/21/working-from-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past five years, I have worked in a traditional office. A few weeks ago, I moved a thousand miles across the country and became a telecommuter. Several months before the move, I started gathering material to try to help me prepare for the new work situation. Here are a few I found useful.</p>

<!--more-->


<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.70decibels.com/homework/">Home Work</a> is an excellent podcast examines the ins and outs of telecommuting and freelancing. I&rsquo;m not a freelancer, so I cherry picked the episodes that seemed most relevant to me. If you&rsquo;re currently an office worker but think you might like to try working from home, check out <a href="http://www.70decibels.com/homework/2012/9/21/027-telecommuting-basics.html">Episode 27 &ndash; Telecommuting Basics</a> and <a href="http://www.70decibels.com/homework/2013/4/19/055-telecommuting.html">Episode 55 &ndash; Telecommuting</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://lifehacker.com/the-beginners-guide-to-working-from-home-733412770">The Beginner&rsquo;s Guide to Working from Home</a> is a recent article that has several good tips for a new home worker.</li>
<li><a href="http://whowritesforyou.com/2013/04/22/working-from-home/">Working From Home</a> covers many of the pitfalls and challenges associated with working from home, and offers several tips on how to make it work.</li>
</ul>


<p>Here&rsquo;s my core advice to anyone about to start telecommuting for the first time. Give some proactive thought and planning to your home office setup, your work/life schedule and boundaries, and your effectiveness as a communicator. Also, try to be aware of what distractions are most problematic for you and take steps to minimize them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Pointless Check-Ins]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/04/27/on-pointless-check-ins/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-27T14:31:48-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/04/27/on-pointless-check-ins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://zerodistraction.com/what-is-the-point-of-the-check-in">What is the Point of the Check In &#10140;</a></p>

<p>I, too, have totally abandoned service such as Foursquare. I don&rsquo;t see the point in publicly announcing when and where I have coffee or sushi.</p>

<p>However, a few months ago I became interested in creating a <strong>private</strong> log of &ldquo;Check-Ins&rdquo;. I wanted something that I could revisit years from now to help me remember what things were like during this era of my life. And some day, this may be interesting to my kids or future grandkids.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I settled using <a href="http://dayoneapp.com">Day One</a> for this purpose. I don&rsquo;t really have much interest in journaling or keeping a diary, but it&rsquo;s well suited for capturing the information I want. In just a few quick touches I have a log entry that contains</p>

<ul>
<li>My location</li>
<li>One or two words about what&rsquo;s happening</li>
<li>A photograph</li>
<li>The current weather at my location</li>
</ul>


<p>Also, the Mac app supports Markdown export, which I like for long-term archival. I also like that the data stays within my control at all times, unlike services such as Path.</p>

<p>So, the end result is a <strong>private</strong> log of places I&rsquo;ve visited, annotated with pictures. Here is a recent entry.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8686982960/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8262/8686982960_798106748d_z.jpg" title="'Day One Entry' 361 640" ></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[launchctl asuser]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/04/24/launchctl-asuser/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-24T23:54:44-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/04/24/launchctl-asuser</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man8/launchd.8.html">launchd</a> provides many ways to configure when and under what conditions a job is started. You can define agents that run for each user, or daemons that run as root outside of a GUI context.</p>

<p>The launchctl command is a convenient way to interface with launchd. Recently I came across a command in the <a href="http://www.opensource.apple.com/source/launchd/launchd-442.26.2/support/launchctl.c">launchctl source code</a> that is not documented in the launchctl man page. The &lsquo;asuser&rsquo; command can apparently be used to &ldquo;Execute a subcommand in the given user&rsquo;s context.&rdquo; This would mean that you could use this from a Launch Daemon to spawn a GUI process for a given user, which could be very useful in certain circumstances.</p>

<p>A quick glance at the code and this looks to be the case. It gets the root bootstrap port, looks up the per user mach port for the given UID, sets the bootstrap port for the current task, set some environment, and then does a fork/exec/waitpid.</p>

<p>Sure enough, if you ssh to a mac as root, you can spawn GUI applications into other users&#8217; consoles. I was even able to run Grab.app and capture images of the user&rsquo;s desktop. Without the asuser command, you get nasty errors like &ldquo;RegisterApplication(), FAILED TO establish the default connection to the WindowServer, CGSDefaultConnection() is NULL.&rdquo;</p>

<p>One days soon I&rsquo;d like to resurrect my <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/Launchctl-API">Launchctl API</a> project and add a few more commands, including this one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Lieu of Ads]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/04/20/in-lieu-of-ads/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-20T00:11:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/04/20/in-lieu-of-ads</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently saw <a href="https://github.com/begriffs/lucre">this project</a> in my news feed and wanted to give it a try. It&rsquo;s a simple rails app that gives you an easy way to accept credit card payments online. I&rsquo;ve never liked the way that ads looked on my site, so I&rsquo;m going to run a &ldquo;tip me&rdquo; button for a while and see how that works.</p>

<p>If you find one of my posts useful, or if you&rsquo;d just like to buy me a coffee, <a href="http://pay-matt.herokuapp.com">give it a try</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google is about to learn a tough lesson]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/03/16/google-is-about-to-learn-a-tough-lesson/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-16T10:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/03/16/google-is-about-to-learn-a-tough-lesson</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://blog.calbucci.com/2013/03/google-is-about-to-learn-tough-lesson.html">Google is about to learn a tough lesson→</a></p>

<p>Some interesting points about social influencers and the Google Reader cancellation. I may not be an &ldquo;influencer&rdquo; at the level of a tech journalist, but I have already taken the first steps toward moving my immediate family to a paid email provider.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cellular Networking on OS X]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/26/cellular-networking-on-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T22:00:02-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/26/cellular-networking-on-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lamenting the lack of cellular-aware APIs in 10.8, <a href="http://www.marco.org/2013/02/26/why-no-4g-macbooks">Marco writes</a>,</p>

<blockquote><p>I was hoping Mountain Lion would add some APIs suggesting cellular data considerations, but it didn’t happen. Maybe 10.9 will.</p></blockquote>


<p>However, Mountain Lion did offer one tiny inkling that cellular awareness in OS X APIs could be on the way. NSURLRequest added <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Cocoa/Reference/Foundation/Classes/NSURLRequest_Class/Reference/Reference.html#//apple_ref/occ/instm/NSURLRequest/allowsCellularAccess">&ndash;(BOOL)allowsCellularAccess</a></p>

<blockquote><p>Returns whether the request is allowed to use the cellular radio (if present).</p><p>**Return Value**<br/>YES if the cellular radio can be used; NO otherwise.</p><p>**Availability**<br/>Available in OS X v10.8 and later.</p></blockquote>


<p>Also, it&rsquo;s interesting that the NSURLRequest.h also exposes the corresponding setter method, which is not linked in Apple&rsquo;s documentation. The comments direct you to &ldquo;pass NO if the receiver should not be allowed to use the built in cellular radios to satisfy the request, YES otherwise.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Then again, this is the Foundation framework we&rsquo;re talking about, so perhaps the inclusion of this method was just a byproduct of the continued convergence of the iOS and Mac APIs. Still, it would be exciting to see full support for cellular connections in Mac OS 10.9.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying Out Octopress 2.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/24/trying-out-octopress-2-dot-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-24T21:45:05-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/24/trying-out-octopress-2-dot-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This site is now running <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/tree/2.1">Octopress 2.1</a> (still in beta). The most notable new feature is its <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/blogging/linklog/">support for linklogs</a>, which is pretty exciting. Apologies if you see any hiccups in the RSS feed while I tinker with the site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Static Hosting Cost]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/04/amazon-static-hosting-cost/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-04T20:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/04/amazon-static-hosting-cost</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A little over a month ago, I <a href="http://mattmorr.is/blog/2012/12/28/hosting-a-naked-domain-on-amazon-s3/">moved this site to Amazon S3 Static Hosting</a>. I&rsquo;ve just received the bill for the first full month using the service. Here are the details.</p>

<!--more-->


<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8445751017/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8236/8445751017_fd12a5bd55_b.jpg"></a></p>

<p>This is for two websites. The &ldquo;Reduced Redundancy&rdquo; portion of the bill has nothing to do with the websites, but is for a bucket where I backup certain files.</p>

<p>So, the real price for hosting two websites on root domains was <strong>$1.1</strong>. Since I have very low traffic, most of the cost was for Amazon&rsquo;s DNS service. You have to use their DNS service if you want to use a root domain, but if you keep the www subdomain, you could use your own DNS provider. In my case, if I weren&rsquo;t using the root domain, my bill would only be about ten cents.</p>

<p>This seems inexpensive, but if you have more than a handful of websites with any meaningful traffic it could start to add up to more than a $9 per month shared hosting plan.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating from LastPass to 1Password]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/01/migrating-from-lastpass-to-1password/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T17:19:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/01/migrating-from-lastpass-to-1password</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I decided to give <a href="https://agilebits.com/onepassword">1Password</a> a try. I&rsquo;ve been a <a href="http://lastpass.com">LastPass</a> user for some time now, but I&rsquo;ve always felt that their iPhone app left much to be desired. The 1Password apps are currently on sale for Macworld 2013, so I figured it&rsquo;s as good a time as any to give it a shot. Here&rsquo;s how I migrated my data from LastPass.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Export CSV from LastPass</h2>

<p>The first step was to get the data out of LastPass. Click the LastPass button in Safari or Chrome, then click &ldquo;Advanced&rdquo;. You should see the following interface. Select &ldquo;Export&rdquo;.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8437083058/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8375/8437083058_a9f9ac60ed.jpg"></a></p>

<p>This will give you a giant plaintext dump of your logins and passwords in CSV format. Save it to disk.</p>

<h2>Importing the CSV Data to 1Password</h2>

<p>Open 1Password on the Mac. From the File menu, choose &ldquo;Import&hellip;&rdquo;. You will see the following interface that begins the import process. Start by selecting &ldquo;CSV or Delimited Text&rdquo; from the dropdown.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8437083628/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8229/8437083628_5f0181ebd0_z.jpg"></a></p>

<p>On the next screen, choose the CSV file that you exported from LastPass, and click &ldquo;Start Import&rdquo;. Then, on the next screen, you just tell 1Password how to interpret the CSV data.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8435998903/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8512/8435998903_1547264bac_z.jpg"></a></p>

<p>There are a few things you have to do on this screen to make things work right. The first line of the CSV file is header information for each column. So, select &ldquo;Start import at line:<strong>1</strong>&rdquo;. Also, there is a dropdown above each column that needs to be set so that 1Password knows how to interpret the colum. In the screenshot, I&rsquo;ve set URL/Location, Username, Password, and Title.</p>

<p>In the next screen, you can review the entries. When you&rsquo;re satisfied, just click &ldquo;Import&rdquo; and it will start populating the 1Password keychain with the lastpass CSV data.</p>

<h2>Securely Remove the CSV File</h2>

<p>This is important. You don&rsquo;t want a plain-text copy of all your credentials sitting on disk.</p>

<p>On OS X, the <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/#documentation/Darwin/Reference/ManPages/man1/rm.1.html">rm</a> command has an option to securely overwrite files before deleting them. The option you want is -P.</p>

<blockquote><p>Overwrite regular files before deleting them.  Files are overwritten three times, first with the byte pattern 0xff, then 0x00, and then 0xff again, before they are deleted.</p></blockquote>


<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8437226198/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8353/8437226198_fba7a5c3f5_o.png"></a></p>

<p>This is an easy way to make reasonably sure that the data is no longer sitting unencrypted on your hard drive.</p>

<h2>Finally</h2>

<p>LastPass has served me well for a long stretch, but 1Password&rsquo;s iOS and Mac apps are too compelling to ignore. I hope this walkthrough has been informative. Feel free to contact me if you find any errors.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glif Plus]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/20/glif-plus/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T14:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/20/glif-plus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoy being our unofficial family photographer. Since the birth of our first son almost three years ago, I&rsquo;ve shot about a terabyte of images and video of our family. Recently, I&rsquo;ve been going through our Aperture library, culling duplicates and deleting bad images, and I&rsquo;ve come to realize two things about the video I&rsquo;ve shot.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First, being the unofficial family photographer, I am in virtually none of the videos or pictures. Now, I don&rsquo;t really mind, but I&rsquo;m sure that my children will want to look back at this footage and see a more complete picture of everyone that was there.</p>

<p>Second, I would really like a way to capture longer videos of family moments. Even an uneventful dinner on a randon Tuesday night will surely be precious footage 30 years from now.</p>

<p>So, to address these two issues, I wanted a way to mount the iPhone on a standard tripod. I settled on the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AAKO646/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=matmor-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AAKO646">Glif Plus</a> by <a href="http://www.studioneat.com/">Studio Neat</a>. My plan is to leave a tripod in a corner nearby, always at-the-ready.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8396066938/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8374/8396066938_a0262f83b7_z.jpg"></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent a few days with it, and so far I quite like it. All the pieces that come in contact with the iPhone are firm, non-scratchy rubber. Also, it feels secure on the tripod; I don&rsquo;t worry that it will fall off.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8394982783/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8232/8394982783_a76285ca16_z.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Also, it&rsquo;s pretty quick to setup. One corner of the phone slides into the rubber base, and then the other piece secures everything together.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8394983957/" ><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8054/8394983957_111193624e_z.jpg"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8396067692/"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8499/8396067692_2a113d715a_z.jpg"></a></p>

<p>Now, when I get home from work, I get to co-star in some home movies along with my wife and kids. Also, as an added bonus, my phone is now much less likely to be dividing my attention when I should be 100% focused on my family.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vicious for Xcode]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/07/vicious-for-xcode/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T20:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/07/vicious-for-xcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;d like to recommend a tool that I&rsquo;ve been using over the past few weeks. <a href="http://viciousapp.com">Vicious</a> is a plugin for Xcode that provides Vi keybindings in the text editor. When I first heard about it, I was skeptical that it could actually deliver on this promise, but I&rsquo;ve been pleasantly surprised. I&rsquo;ve used Vi for years, so I have a great deal of Vi muscle memory stored up in my fingers. Give it a try if you know Vi and have to work with Xcode.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 Goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/01/2013-goals/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/01/2013-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are a few of the goals I&rsquo;ve set for 2013.</p>

<ol>
<li>Post at least one blog entry per week.</li>
<li>Read 12 books: either fiction or nonfiction.</li>
<li>Learn a new technology by building a new app or service. Currently I&rsquo;m thinking of doing something on heroku with Rails.</li>
</ol>


<p>What goals are you setting for 2013?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Doc Vault]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/01/doc-vault/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T10:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/01/doc-vault</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently launched my second personal app on the iOS App Store. <a href="http://bit.ly/X8PuYu">Doc Vault</a> is a way to capture documents that you don&rsquo;t want cluttering up your camera roll, or automaticaly sent to Photo Stream or some other third-party service.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Capture, Retrieve, Export</h2>

<p>Doc Vault allows you to do three simple things:</p>

<ol>
<li>Capture an image of a textual document.</li>
<li>Search for a particular document by entering text found in the image.</li>
<li>Manually export a document to a third party service of your choosing.</li>
</ol>


<h2>Doc Vault Interface</h2>

<p>These first two images illustrate Doc Vault&rsquo;s search capability. A number of images have been scanned, and a search for the term &ldquo;insurance&rdquo; has limited the displayed results to a single result. Also, each document has a footnote that indicates if OCR processing has completed and the document is searchable.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8334476862"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8219/8334476862_49a1cf57b1_z.jpg" width="361" height="640"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8333417327"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8081/8333417327_23b68ce8ee_z.jpg" width="361" height="640"></a></p>

<p>The third screenshot shows the activity sheet in which you can export a document from the app. Currently, I support Email, Print, Copy to Pasteboard, and Dropbox. Evernote and other services are coming soon.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8333314989"><img class="center" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8219/8333314989_de6493b695_z.jpg" width="361" height="640"></a></p>

<h2>Now, Why Have an App For This?</h2>

<p>On iOS, most apps take the reasonable assumption that images in the Camera Roll are photograps of friends, family, food, or flowers. But just think for a moment about what happens after the picture is taken.</p>

<p>If you have Photo Stream enabled, your image is automatically sent to Apple&rsquo;s servers and then forwarded to your Macs and other iOS devices. Photo Stream is hardly the place for credit card statements, social security card numbers, or other sensitive information. Just imagine an image of your credit card statement appearing in the slideshow of your Apple TV.</p>

<p>Also, several high-profile apps, most notably <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/facebook/id284882215?mt=8">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google+/id447119634?mt=8">Google+</a> have features which automatically upload images from the Camera Roll to their respective services. Even if opt-in to these features, it&rsquo;s unlikely that you want to send an image that contains your home address to Facebook.</p>

<p>Doc Vault allows you to capture images that contain sensitive information like this without the worry that it will be sent somewhere without your knowledge. Then later, when you need to go back and find a document you&rsquo;ve scanned, just search for a word found in the image. Then, if you decide to send it somewhere, you can do so.</p>

<h2>Future Work</h2>

<p>I have many features and improvements planned for Doc Vault. First there are several other services for which I&rsquo;d like to add export support. Also, there are some iOS-specific performance improvements that I&rsquo;m working on for the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/tesseract-ocr/">tesseract</a> library, which Doc Vault uses to scan images for text. (That effort will go up on github once it&rsquo;s ready). Finally, per my mother&rsquo;s request, I&rsquo;d like to add a way to scan a multi-page document and keep all the pages associated inside the app&rsquo;s data store.</p>

<h2>Finally</h2>

<p>Feel free to give Doc Vault a try and let me know what you think. Also, if you&rsquo;re a developer and would like to beta-test, shoot me an email at [my first name] @ [this domain].</p>

<center><a href="http://bit.ly/X8PuYu"><img src="http://mattmorr.is/images/Available_on_the_App_Store_Badge.svg" width="405" height="120" style="border-style: none"></a></center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hosting a Naked Domain on Amazon S3]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/12/28/hosting-a-naked-domain-on-amazon-s3/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-28T21:46:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/12/28/hosting-a-naked-domain-on-amazon-s3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few months ago I experimented with hosting this website on <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3">Amazon S3</a>. It&rsquo;s trivial to setup an s3 bucket as a website, and <a href="http://ponyho.st">ponyHost</a> makes it a breeze to deploy an <a href="http://www.octopress.org">Octopress</a> website to the bucket. Static HTML/CSS + S3 hosting make for a very snappy website. However, at that time there was no clean way to use S3 to host a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Root_domain">root domain</a>, so I abandoned the effort.</p>

<p>Then just this morning, Amazon announced support for root domains with Amazon S3 hosted websites.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I decided to give it a try during lunch. I followed <a href="http://docs.amazonwebservices.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/website-hosting-custom-domain-walkthrough.html">these instructions</a> and in less than an hour I was all finished, save for DNS propagation. This site is now hosted on Amazon&rsquo;s lightning-fast infrastructure. And if I need to, I can fail back to my shared hosting provider by simply changing the DNS nameservers at my registrar.</p>

<p>One lingering concern I have is cost. Although S3 prices are very economical under normal circumstances, the &ldquo;Data Transfer Out&rdquo; component of the pricing means that my monthly bill&rsquo;s theoretical maximum is effectively infinite. Expensive accidents involving Amazon S3 are not without <a href="http://www.behind-the-enemy-lines.com/2012/04/google-attack-how-i-self-attacked.html">precedent</a>. Even a single individual with an axe to grind and a 10 megabit home internet connection could do non-trivial damage to my wallet over the course of a month.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m sure there are ways to configure logging and/or notifications in a manner that would let me guard against such accidents or attacks, but I have not explored this yet. I&rsquo;ll take a look at that over the weekend. In the meantime, please let me know if you happen to see any issue with the site.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kid Vids Rejection]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/09/30/kid-vids-rejection/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T14:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/09/30/kid-vids-rejection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after the iPhone 5 announcement, I began updating <a href="http://bit.ly/NeDHS2">Kid Vids</a> for compatibility with the larger screen. Since Kid Vids is a video player, I was especially excited to take advantage of the 16x9 aspect ratio.</p>

<p>To my surprise, this update was rejected due to copyright concerns.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First I&rsquo;ll explain how this simple app works. Given a YouTube playlist ID, it will play videos from that playlist. That&rsquo;s really it. It doesn&rsquo;t let you browse YouTube and it doesn&rsquo;t offer a way to search for videos. I do this using Google&rsquo;s <a href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/code#ObjectiveC">Objective C Client Library</a>.</p>

<p>The functionality and obvious limitations of this app are completely intentional. I wanted a way to play a selection of hand-picked videos for my kids without the possibility of an inappropriate video appearing as a &ldquo;Related Video.&rdquo; And the introduction of Guided Access in iOS 6 makes it an even better solution to my original problem.</p>

<p>Fast forward to last week. I got a push notification from the iTunes Connect informing me that the submission had been rejected. Strange, I thought, since this was perhaps the 8th update to the app and it had never had a problem before. Once I logged into iTunes Connect, I found this explanation:</p>

<blockquote><p>We found that your app contains features that may infringe on rights owned by Children&rsquo;s Television Workshop, which is not in compliance with the App Store Review Guidelines.</p>

<p>Specifically, we noticed your app contains clips and videos from the Sesame Street television series.</p></blockquote>

<p>But my app bundle does not contain any clips and video whatsoever. It just streams video from YouTube. It does include a few playlist IDs that I offer as a way to get started quickly in the event that the user does not have a YouTube account at the ready. Since this is an app targeted at children, Sesame Street factored heavily into my selection.</p>

<p>The videos that I include are all from <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/SesameStreet">Sesame Street&rsquo;s public YouTube page</a>. You can even play them through Mobile Safari, the <em>new</em> YouTube.app, or any of the other countless iOS applications that include YouTube functionality.</p>

<p>So, rather than to rework all my presets, I decided to submit an appeal to the App Review Board. I don&rsquo;t see a way to get the exact text of my appeal back from the website, but this was the gist of my argument:</p>

<ul>
<li>The Kid Vids app bundle&rsquo;s payload does not contain any video at all.</li>
<li>It only plays (streams) public content from YouTube.</li>
<li>I believe Kid Vids to be fully compliant with the <a href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/terms">YouTube Developer Terms of Service</a>.</li>
<li>The sale of an API client is explicitly permitted in Section 1.2 of these terms.</li>
</ul>


<p>After a few days, I received this friendly, albeit somewhat terse, reply:</p>

<blockquote><p>Thank you for submitting an appeal to the App Review Board for the review of your app, Kid Vids.</p>

<p>We have completed the evaluation of your appeal and have determined that the review findings of 9/19/12 are appropriate.</p>

<p>While this version of your app will not be posted to the App Store, we hope you will consider revising your app to address the issue and bring your into compliance with the Guidelines.</p></blockquote>

<p>I can only imagine that the App Review Board feels it is simply not worth risking litigation by approving an app that <em>seems</em> to violate a copyright. I&rsquo;m sure if I were in their shoes, I would be equally cautious. On the other hand, I wonder how many &ldquo;Wang Ting&rdquo; apps are still available on the App Store. (See this <a href="http://iphonedevelopment.blogspot.com/2012/08/irksome-but-nothing-new.html">article by Jeff Lamarche</a>)</p>

<p>So, I &ldquo;turned off&rdquo; Sesame Street in the app and resubmitted. Not a big deal in the end. Hopefully it goes through this time without a hitch. But what if the reviewer for the next update finds a new supposed violation with some other video? It would be tiresome to have to go through this song and dance for every update submission.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interception Source Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/08/22/interception-source-code/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T21:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/08/22/interception-source-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In light of the recent <a href="https://dev.twitter.com/blog/changes-coming-to-twitter-api">announcement</a> regarding version 1.1 of the Twitter API, it now makes sense why clicking on a Twitter notification in notification center launches Safari. To make sure that they can show us ads when they want to, they&rsquo;re driving as many people as they can to the official Twitter UI.</p>

<p>So, I&rsquo;ve decided to go ahead and push the <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/Interception">code</a> for Interception to github in case anyone wants to enhance it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notification Center and Native Twitter Clients]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/29/notification-center-and-native-twitter-clients/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/29/notification-center-and-native-twitter-clients</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Late last week, I finally got around to setting up Twitter as an account on Mountain Lion. I was disappointed to see that clicking a Twitter notification launches the default web browser and not Twitter.app or any other client. I do not enjoy using Twitter&rsquo;s web interface, so I wrote a simple application that forwards these clicks to a native Twitter application of your choice.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Quick Start</h2>

<p>If this sounds like something that you would find useful, <a href="http://bit.ly/RjnPQz">download the beta</a> and give it a try. The application is a single dialog that asks for your preferred Twitter client. Click &lsquo;Okay&rsquo; and you&rsquo;re all set. There should be no need to run the app again unless you want to switch to a different client.</p>

<center><img src="http://mmorris.github.io/downloads/images/interception_ui.png"></center>


<h2>Disclaimer</h2>

<p>This software should be considered very &ldquo;beta.&rdquo; If things get weird and you find you can&rsquo;t open http URLs anymore or something like that, just delete the .app and <a href="http://www.twitter.com/boxel">let me know</a>.</p>

<h2>How It Works</h2>

<p>Interception registers itself as the default handler the URLs that are invoked when you click on a Twitter notification. If it notices a Twitter URL is being loaded by Launch Services, it catches the request and forwards it to the native twitter client you have chosen. All other URLs are silently passed as-is to the default web browser. A previous version of Interception set itself as the default http URL handler for the system, but this is no longer necessary.</p>

<h2>Known Issues and Next Steps</h2>

<p>Interception currently supports only the following Twitter clients:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://tapbots.com/tweetbot_mac/">Tweetbot for Mac</a></li>
<li>Twitter.app</li>
<li>Tweet Deck</li>
<li><a href="http://hibariapp.com">Hibari</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Currently Interception is just hard-coded with the bundle identifiers for each of these apps. In a future version, I might add a &ldquo;Choose App&rdquo; button which would let the user. If your favorite native Twitter client is not one of these four, please let me know.</p>

<p>Also, Twitter mentions and direct messages should land the user on different views inside the targeted Twitter app. I began to wire this up, but it seems that the Tweetbot for Mac public alpha is not yet honoring the <a href="http://tapbots.com/blog/development/tweetbot-url-scheme">Tweetbot URL Scheme</a>, so I put that functionality on hold for all clients. Tweetbot is awesome, and this will be the next feature I add.</p>

<p>I have created a <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/Interception">project</a> over on <a href="https://github.com">Github</a> where I will host the code. I have not posted it yet for two reasons. First, I did this in a bit of a hurry and I would like to clean up the code before I throw it out into the wild. Second, if our local Cocoaheads chapter gets going in the next month or two, I might like to present the project at a meeting and then release the source code and slides all at the same time.</p>

<h2>Wrap-Up</h2>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/RjnPQz">Download It Here</a>. Feedback is welcome.</p>

<p>I realize that if you&rsquo;re favorite Twitter client is in the Mac App Store, it can use push notifications in Mountain Lion, in which case Interception won&rsquo;t really be that useful. I&rsquo;ve really been enoying Tweetbot for Mac, but it&rsquo;s currently in alpha and doesn&rsquo;t yet support remote push notifications. This application grew out of a script I wrote because I wanted to be able to launch Tweetbot from a notification even if Tweetbot wasn&rsquo;t already running.</p>

<p>Incidentally, I&rsquo;ve lost track of how many times I typed &ldquo;Inception&rdquo; while writing this post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Experience with LASIK]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/14/my-experience-with-lasik/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-14T12:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/14/my-experience-with-lasik</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two months ago, in preparation for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LASIK">LASIK</a> eye surgery, I searched the internet for accounts of people&rsquo;s experiences with the procedure. I found a wide variety of results, most of which were positive. Since I didn&rsquo;t find anything from the point of view of a professional programmer, I will leave my account here.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>The Facts</h2>

<ul>
<li>Pre-surgery, I was highly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Myopia">myopic</a> with a prescription of -8.75 in both eyes.</li>
<li>Pre-surgery, my vision was correctable to 20/15 (better than 20/20)</li>
<li>Date of surgery: May 30th, 2012 @ 7:30am</li>
<li>Post-surgery prescription, measured the day after surgery:

<ul>
<li>Left Eye:  -0.25</li>
<li>Right Eye: -0.75</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;m told that &ndash;.25 is effectively 20/20.</p>

<h2>My Daily Routine</h2>

<p>I believe that <strong>how</strong> you use your eyes every day is an important factor to consider when thinking about LASIK. For someone in a career that requires almost constant use of a computer, having clear and reliable vision is very important. To give a clearer picture of my results and whether or not you can draw any conclusions from my impressions, here is a rough outline of my typical day.</p>

<ul>
<li>Awake at 5:45</li>
<li>Leave house by 6:45</li>
<li>40+ minute commute</li>
<li>At work: 8+ hours of programming</li>
<li>Workout during lunch</li>
<li>40+ minute commute</li>
<li>Dinner + family time.</li>
<li>Once kids are asleep: 4+ hours of programming on personal projects.</li>
</ul>


<p>(Note: This is the fullest possible schedule. I can&rsquo;t pull this off every day.)</p>

<p>During the pre-surgery interviews with the surgeon, I explained that I am a professional programmer and asked if I could be expected to return to work the next day. Answer: yes.</p>

<h2>The Surgery</h2>

<p>The surgery itself was not a big deal. It was a little uncomfortable at one point when a suction device is attached to the eye, but that didn&rsquo;t last long. When I first got up from the opterating table, everything appeared as if I were underwater. This was, in fact, because there is actually fluid in the eye that drains away over the next 24-48 hours.</p>

<h2>Recovery, Day 0</h2>

<p>After the surgery, I was driven home by a family member. There was no pain, but my vision was cloudy and I would have been unable to drive. My two boys were at home with a babysitter. Once home, I attempted to close my eyes and rest, at the recommendation of the surgeon.</p>

<p>Later that day there was more discomfort, but my vision was already beginning to clear. I cooked the boys dinner and got them ready for bed with no problem.</p>

<p>Once they were asleep in bed, I sat down at the computer to check my email and maybe try to work on some of my apps. <strong>I was barely able to read email.</strong> Needless to say, I was a little concerned, since I was scheduled to return to work the next day. But I decided not to worry about it for the time being, hoping that 8 hours of sleep would give my eyes time to rest and recover.</p>

<h2>Recovery, Day 1: Halos</h2>

<p>The next day I realized that I was seeing the dreaded &ldquo;halo&rdquo; effect that I had read about online. Around every light source, I saw a very noticeable ring of light. It turns out that this didn&rsquo;t really bother me when I was doing most &ldquo;normal&rdquo; activities. Computer screens, however, turned out to be a problem. They emit light, and when reading text on screen, each character produced its own halo, and every halo overlapped with the ones adjacent to it. This created an unbearable blurring effect that made it very difficult to read on-screen text.</p>

<p>In fact, I went in for a 24 hour followup that day. My prescription was measured using a autorefractor, and my vision was determined to be very close to 20/20. However, I was almost completely unable to read the letters on the eye chart. The eye chart appeared to be an LCD backlit display, and this was producing haloing effects around the letters.</p>

<p>I did manage to get to work that day. However, it was frustrating becuase I had to place the screens mere inches from my face and increase the font in Xcode to rediculous sizes. It was so large that I suspected people could read my code from the hallway by my office.</p>

<h2>Recovery, Week 1</h2>

<p>The halo effect persisted well into the first week. It was still difficult to read a computer screen, but I found that if I used the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000VS1HSA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000VS1HSA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=matmor-20">lubricant eye drops</a> recommended by the doctor, it helped a great deal. Yes, the drops temporarily cleared my vision. I found that if I used the drops every 45 minutes or so, I could code the whole day without getting too frustrated.</p>

<h2>One Month Later</h2>

<p>At times I still have to use the lubricant eye drops in order to use a computer, but my vision has gradually improved to the point that I somteimes go several hours without having to do so.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been asked several times how satisfied I am with the procedure. I think that if I had any type of job that doesn&rsquo;t require reading code on a screen for 10+ hours a day, I would be 99% satisfied. As this is not the case, I would probably say that I am 85% satisfied.</p>

<p>To this date, I still feel that my vision continues to improve. If you&rsquo;ve recently had LASIK and are concerned because your vision is still blurry, your eyes may still be healing. Try not to worry.</p>

<h2>Tips</h2>

<ul>
<li>Close your eyes and rest as much as possible on the first day. I think I tried to do too much that first day and I wonder if it slowed my recovery.</li>
<li>If you experience halos and have trouble reading a computer screen, try the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000VS1HSA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000VS1HSA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=matmor-20">lubricant eye drops</a>.</li>
<li>Use them frequently, even if the dryness doesn&rsquo;t bother you.</li>
<li><strong>Try to schedule a short vacation from work beginning the day of your surgery. If this is not possible, try to schedule the surgery right before a 3-day weekend.</strong> Reading a computer screen as part of a demanding job was stressful during these first days, but driving, cooking, playing with the kids, etc. was not a problem at all. Drive to the coast and get some rest.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fun Fact</h2>

<p>Radial Keratotomy, a predecessor to the LASIK procedure, was discovered by accident after a young boy fell off his bycicle and broke his glasses. Some time after the doctor had removed the shards of glass from his eye, his visual acuity had improved. [<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radial_keratotomy#Development">source</a>]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
