<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mac | Matt Morris]]></title>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/categories/mac/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-20T10:41:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mmorris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cellular Networking on OS X]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/26/cellular-networking-on-os-x/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T22:00:02-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/02/26/cellular-networking-on-os-x</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Lamenting the lack of cellular-aware APIs in 10.8, <a href="http://www.marco.org/2013/02/26/why-no-4g-macbooks">Marco writes</a>,
<blockquote><p>I was hoping Mountain Lion would add some APIs suggesting cellular data considerations, but it didn’t happen. Maybe 10.9 will.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>However, Mountain Lion did offer one tiny inkling that cellular awareness in OS X APIs could be on the way. NSURLRequest added <a href="https://developer.apple.com/library/mac/documentation/Cocoa/Reference/Foundation/Classes/NSURLRequest_Class/Reference/Reference.html#//apple_ref/occ/instm/NSURLRequest/allowsCellularAccess">&ndash;(BOOL)allowsCellularAccess</a>
<blockquote><p>Returns whether the request is allowed to use the cellular radio (if present).</p></p><p><p><strong>Return Value</strong><br/>YES if the cellular radio can be used; NO otherwise.</p></p><p><p><strong>Availability</strong><br/>Available in OS X v10.8 and later.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Also, it&rsquo;s interesting that the NSURLRequest.h also exposes the corresponding setter method, which is not linked in Apple&rsquo;s documentation. The comments direct you to &ldquo;pass NO if the receiver should not be allowed to use the built in cellular radios to satisfy the request, YES otherwise.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Then again, this is the Foundation framework we&rsquo;re talking about, so perhaps the inclusion of this method was just a byproduct of the continued convergence of the iOS and Mac APIs. Still, it would be exciting to see full support for cellular connections in Mac OS 10.9.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interception Source Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/08/22/interception-source-code/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T21:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/08/22/interception-source-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In light of the recent <a href="https://dev.twitter.com/blog/changes-coming-to-twitter-api">announcement</a> regarding version 1.1 of the Twitter API, it now makes sense why clicking on a Twitter notification in notification center launches Safari. To make sure that they can show us ads when they want to, they&rsquo;re driving as many people as they can to the official Twitter UI.</p>

<p>So, I&rsquo;ve decided to go ahead and push the <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/Interception">code</a> for Interception to github in case anyone wants to enhance it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notification Center and Native Twitter Clients]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/29/notification-center-and-native-twitter-clients/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/29/notification-center-and-native-twitter-clients</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Late last week, I finally got around to setting up Twitter as an account on Mountain Lion. I was disappointed to see that clicking a Twitter notification launches the default web browser and not Twitter.app or any other client. I do not enjoy using Twitter&rsquo;s web interface, so I wrote a simple application that forwards these clicks to a native Twitter application of your choice.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Quick Start</h2>

<p>If this sounds like something that you would find useful, <a href="http://bit.ly/RjnPQz">download the beta</a> and give it a try. The application is a single dialog that asks for your preferred Twitter client. Click &lsquo;Okay&rsquo; and you&rsquo;re all set. There should be no need to run the app again unless you want to switch to a different client.</p>

<center><img src="/downloads/images/interception_ui.png"></center>


<h2>Disclaimer</h2>

<p>This software should be considered very &ldquo;beta.&rdquo; If things get weird and you find you can&rsquo;t open http URLs anymore or something like that, just delete the .app and <a href="http://www.twitter.com/boxel">let me know</a>.</p>

<h2>How It Works</h2>

<p>Interception registers itself as the default handler the URLs that are invoked when you click on a Twitter notification. If it notices a Twitter URL is being loaded by Launch Services, it catches the request and forwards it to the native twitter client you have chosen. All other URLs are silently passed as-is to the default web browser. A previous version of Interception set itself as the default http URL handler for the system, but this is no longer necessary.</p>

<h2>Known Issues and Next Steps</h2>

<p>Interception currently supports only the following Twitter clients:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://tapbots.com/tweetbot_mac/">Tweetbot for Mac</a></li>
<li>Twitter.app</li>
<li>Tweet Deck</li>
<li><a href="http://hibariapp.com">Hibari</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Currently Interception is just hard-coded with the bundle identifiers for each of these apps. In a future version, I might add a &ldquo;Choose App&rdquo; button which would let the user. If your favorite native Twitter client is not one of these four, please let me know.</p>

<p>Also, Twitter mentions and direct messages should land the user on different views inside the targeted Twitter app. I began to wire this up, but it seems that the Tweetbot for Mac public alpha is not yet honoring the <a href="http://tapbots.com/blog/development/tweetbot-url-scheme">Tweetbot URL Scheme</a>, so I put that functionality on hold for all clients. Tweetbot is awesome, and this will be the next feature I add.</p>

<p>I have created a <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/Interception">project</a> over on <a href="https://github.com">Github</a> where I will host the code. I have not posted it yet for two reasons. First, I did this in a bit of a hurry and I would like to clean up the code before I throw it out into the wild. Second, if our local Cocoaheads chapter gets going in the next month or two, I might like to present the project at a meeting and then release the source code and slides all at the same time.</p>

<h2>Wrap-Up</h2>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/RjnPQz">Download It Here</a>. Feedback is welcome.</p>

<p>I realize that if you&rsquo;re favorite Twitter client is in the Mac App Store, it can use push notifications in Mountain Lion, in which case Interception won&rsquo;t really be that useful. I&rsquo;ve really been enoying Tweetbot for Mac, but it&rsquo;s currently in alpha and doesn&rsquo;t yet support remote push notifications. This application grew out of a script I wrote because I wanted to be able to launch Tweetbot from a notification even if Tweetbot wasn&rsquo;t already running.</p>

<p>Incidentally, I&rsquo;ve lost track of how many times I typed &ldquo;Inception&rdquo; while writing this post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DuckDuckGo for Safari]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/04/11/duckduckgo-for-safari/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T20:34:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/04/11/duckduckgo-for-safari</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://duckduckgo.com">DuckDuckGo</a> is a popular alternative to Google Search. Unfortunately it&rsquo;s not one of the search engines supported in Safari by default. Their <a href="http://help.duckduckgo.com/customer/portal/articles/255650">instructions</a> detail how to manually edit the /etc/hosts file to trick Safari into using DuckDuckGo instead of Yahoo.</p>

<p>The problem is that ceratin 3rd party applications, most notably the Cisco VPN Client, modify /etc/hosts in order to accomplish their purpose. In the case of the Cisco VPN Client, the custom DuckDuckGo/Yahoo entry is lost whenever this happens.</p>

<p>This Launch Daemon solves this problem by monitoring /etc/hosts, and adding the entry back if it&rsquo;s removed.  If you&rsquo;ve had this problem, check out the <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/DuckDuckGoDaemon">project</a> over on github and give it a try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matias Tactile Pro 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/03/04/matias-tactile-pro-3/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T11:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/03/04/matias-tactile-pro-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been using the <a href="http://www.apple.com/keyboard/">Apple Wireless Keyboard</a> for some time now. I really liked it when I first started using it, but recently I&rsquo;ve become dissatisfied with it for various reasons. I&rsquo;ve even started to blame it for some pain I&rsquo;ve been having in my finger joints. So, a few weeks ago I decided to try a 3rd party Mac keyboard. I ordered a <a href="http://amzn.to/I4uB3o">Tactile Pro 3</a>, and here are my thoughts.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>What&rsquo;s Wrong with the Apple Aluminum Keyboard?</h2>

<p>My biggest complaint about the Apple keyboards is that the keys have a short &ldquo;travel time.&rdquo;  I&rsquo;m using &ldquo;travel time&rdquo; to mean the time between the instant a finger begins pressing a key to the time that a character is registered by the system. The current line of Apple keyboards have very short keys, and it requires a very short press to register a keystrike.</p>

<p>I know that many pepole like a short travel time because it enables them to touch type very fast. For me, the net effect is that it often feels like I&rsquo;m slamming my fingers on the desk. I&rsquo;ve started to attribute this to some aches and pains that I&rsquo;ve recently felt in my finger joints.</p>

<p>My next complaint is that it&rsquo;s very narrow, and very light. Because it&rsquo;s so narrow, it&rsquo;s not easy for me to use it on my lap. I have to force my legs together so that&rsquo;s it&rsquo;s not constantly slipping.</p>

<h2>Matias Tactile Pro 3</h2>

<p>The <a href="http://amzn.to/I4uB3o">Tactile Pro 3</a> is a full sized Mac keyboard. It has 15 physical function keys, volume buttons, and a num pad. It also touts three high-speed USB 2 ports that are capable of delivering power to other peripherals.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/6963469393/lightbox"><img class="<a" src="href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7182/6963469393_43dd24cfeb_z.jpg">http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7182/6963469393_43dd24cfeb_z.jpg</a>" width="640" height="256" title="&lsquo;Tactile Pro 3&rsquo; &lsquo;Tactile Pro 3&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<p>I got the Silver and Black &ndash; Limited Edition, and I&rsquo;m pretty pleased with how it looks. I&rsquo;m also happy to find that its USB cable is long enough to reach around to my tower without having to use an extension. And we&rsquo;re all aware of Apple&rsquo;s spitefully non-compatible USB extension cables.</p>

<h2>The Keys</h2>

<p>This keyboard has much taller keys than the Apple keyboards. I&rsquo;d say 5-6 times the height. This provides a longer keypress &ldquo;travel time&rdquo; and gives the typing center of my brain a chance to get ready to pullback from the keypress. I also like they way that the keys press &ldquo;up&rdquo; against your finger during the entire keystroke. Also, the tops of the keys are concave, which does seem to help me keep my hands in the right position.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/6963468995/" title="Tactile Pro 3 by Matt Morris, on Flickr"><img class="<a" src="href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7048/6963468995_24d6403a57_z.jpg">http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7048/6963468995_24d6403a57_z.jpg</a>" width="640" height="425" title="&lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 Num Pad&rsquo; &lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 Num Pad&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<h2>Wide-ness</h2>

<p>With the arrow keys set aside from the letter keys and the numpad off to the right, this keyboard is much wider than the Apple wireless keyboard. I don&rsquo;t have to hold my legs and arms so awkwardly together when using it in my lap. The downside to this is that it takes up more real estate on my desk, which is often inhabited by two laptops, two widescreen monitors, and an external hard drive.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/6963469213/lightbox" title="Tactile Pro 3 vs Apple Wireless Keyboard by Matt Morris, on Flickr"> <img class="<a" src="href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/6963469213_754e0cf975_z.jpg">http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/6963469213_754e0cf975_z.jpg</a>" width="640" height="426" title="&lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 vs Apple Wireless Keyboard&rsquo; &lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 vs Apple Wireless Keyboard&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<h2>Clickety Clickety Clack!</h2>

<p>The Tactile Pro 3 is, if nothing else, loud. A keypress makes several distinct sounds as you press. I like this because it&rsquo;s more signaling that my brain can use in determining the right moment to release a key and move on.  I find that I am able to do a softer keypress even when I&rsquo;m typing at full speed. But more than that, it&rsquo;s just really really fun to work on a clicky keyboard.  Maybe this is just nostalga for the Apple II or Apple Extended.</p>

<p>The big potential downside of the loudness is that it might be distracting to your office mate, or even to coworkers several dozen meters down the hall. This is something that I sometimes worry about, and I&rsquo;m still trying to decide if I should buy my office mate a pair of noice cancelling headphones.
<blockquote><p>I say your colleagues should learn to love your loud keyboard. It&rsquo;s a sign that you&rsquo;re hard at work. &ldquo;Hey Dave&rsquo;s working, listen to Dave&hellip; Holy hell, Dave&rsquo;s getting some shit done, I&rsquo;m gonna get back to work.&rdquo;</p><footer><strong>John Gruber</strong> <cite>The Talk Show #81 <a href="http://5by5.tv/talkshow/81">http://5by5.tv/talkshow/81</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<h2>Other Niceties</h2>

<ul>
<li>Laser Etched Keys (should show less wear than painted)</li>
<li>Symbols and Special Characters are also on the key surface</li>
<li>No limit on the number of simultaneous keystrokes</li>
</ul>


<h2>Negatives?</h2>

<p>There are a few keys at the edge of the keyboard which sometimes exhibit additional friction while the key is being pressed down. I suspect that it&rsquo;s because my hand is far from the key, and as a result my finger is not striking the key at an angle perpendicular to the keyboard&rsquo;s back plane. I&rsquo;m exerting some force to the side, and it&rsquo;s causing the key to rub against the housing a little. But this doesn&rsquo;t bother me too often, and maybe with some practice I can develop the muscle memory to avoid it completely.</p>

<p>Lastly, the frame isn&rsquo;t quite as solid and heavy as I would consider ideal. If you&rsquo;re keyboard isn&rsquo;t the first thing you grab when a home intruder is kicking down your door, you may have the wrong keyboard.</p>

<h2>Price</h2>

<p>At 150 USD, this isn&rsquo;t a trivial purchase. But if you&rsquo;re a professional that uses a keyboard all day, day and night, all year round, then it&rsquo;s really not that much to spend on the right tools. And even if there&rsquo;s no <strong>real</strong> speed increase with a clicky keyboard, I still feel it&rsquo;s worth it to have tools that aren&rsquo;t a daily annoyance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
