<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: reviews | Matt Morris]]></title>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/categories/reviews/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-24T14:36:45-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mmorris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glif Plus]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/20/glif-plus/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T14:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/20/glif-plus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I enjoy being our unofficial family photographer. Since the birth of our first son almost three years ago, I&rsquo;ve shot about a terabyte of images and video of our family. Recently, I&rsquo;ve been going through our Aperture library, culling duplicates and deleting bad images, and I&rsquo;ve come to realize two things about the video I&rsquo;ve shot.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First, being the unofficial family photographer, I am in virtually none of the videos or pictures. Now, I don&rsquo;t really mind, but I&rsquo;m sure that my children will want to look back at this footage and see a more complete picture of everyone that was there.</p>

<p>Second, I would really like a way to capture longer videos of family moments. Even an uneventful dinner on a randon Tuesday night will surely be precious footage 30 years from now.</p>

<p>So, to address these two issues, I wanted a way to mount the iPhone on a standard tripod. I settled on the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AAKO646/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=matmor-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B00AAKO646">Glif Plus</a> by <a href="http://www.studioneat.com/">Studio Neat</a>. My plan is to leave a tripod in a corner nearby, always at-the-ready.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8396066938/"><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8374/8396066938_a0262f83b7_z.jpg">http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8374/8396066938_a0262f83b7_z.jpg</a>"></a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent a few days with it, and so far I quite like it. All the pieces that come in contact with the iPhone are firm, non-scratchy rubber. Also, it feels secure on the tripod; I don&rsquo;t worry that it will fall off.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8394982783/"><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8232/8394982783_a76285ca16_z.jpg">http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8232/8394982783_a76285ca16_z.jpg</a>"></a></p>

<p>Also, it&rsquo;s pretty quick to setup. One corner of the phone slides into the rubber base, and then the other piece secures everything together.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8394983957/" ><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8054/8394983957_111193624e_z.jpg">http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8054/8394983957_111193624e_z.jpg</a>"></a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/8396067692/"><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8499/8396067692_2a113d715a_z.jpg">http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8499/8396067692_2a113d715a_z.jpg</a>"></a></p>

<p>Now, when I get home from work, I get to co-star in some home movies along with my wife and kids. Also, as an added bonus, my phone is now much less likely to be dividing my attention when I should be 100% focused on my family.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vicious for Xcode]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/07/vicious-for-xcode/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-07T20:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/01/07/vicious-for-xcode</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;d like to recommend a tool that I&rsquo;ve been using over the past few weeks. <a href="http://viciousapp.com">Vicious</a> is a plugin for Xcode that provides Vi keybindings in the text editor. When I first heard about it, I was skeptical that it could actually deliver on this promise, but I&rsquo;ve been pleasantly surprised. I&rsquo;ve used Vi for years, so I have a great deal of Vi muscle memory stored up in my fingers. Give it a try if you know Vi and have to work with Xcode.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Matias Tactile Pro 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/03/04/matias-tactile-pro-3/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T11:22:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/03/04/matias-tactile-pro-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been using the <a href="http://www.apple.com/keyboard/">Apple Wireless Keyboard</a> for some time now. I really liked it when I first started using it, but recently I&rsquo;ve become dissatisfied with it for various reasons. I&rsquo;ve even started to blame it for some pain I&rsquo;ve been having in my finger joints. So, a few weeks ago I decided to try a 3rd party Mac keyboard. I ordered a <a href="http://amzn.to/I4uB3o">Tactile Pro 3</a>, and here are my thoughts.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>What&rsquo;s Wrong with the Apple Aluminum Keyboard?</h2>

<p>My biggest complaint about the Apple keyboards is that the keys have a short &ldquo;travel time.&rdquo;  I&rsquo;m using &ldquo;travel time&rdquo; to mean the time between the instant a finger begins pressing a key to the time that a character is registered by the system. The current line of Apple keyboards have very short keys, and it requires a very short press to register a keystrike.</p>

<p>I know that many pepole like a short travel time because it enables them to touch type very fast. For me, the net effect is that it often feels like I&rsquo;m slamming my fingers on the desk. I&rsquo;ve started to attribute this to some aches and pains that I&rsquo;ve recently felt in my finger joints.</p>

<p>My next complaint is that it&rsquo;s very narrow, and very light. Because it&rsquo;s so narrow, it&rsquo;s not easy for me to use it on my lap. I have to force my legs together so that&rsquo;s it&rsquo;s not constantly slipping.</p>

<h2>Matias Tactile Pro 3</h2>

<p>The <a href="http://amzn.to/I4uB3o">Tactile Pro 3</a> is a full sized Mac keyboard. It has 15 physical function keys, volume buttons, and a num pad. It also touts three high-speed USB 2 ports that are capable of delivering power to other peripherals.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/6963469393/lightbox"><img class="<a" src="href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7182/6963469393_43dd24cfeb_z.jpg">http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7182/6963469393_43dd24cfeb_z.jpg</a>" width="640" height="256" title="&lsquo;Tactile Pro 3&rsquo; &lsquo;Tactile Pro 3&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<p>I got the Silver and Black &ndash; Limited Edition, and I&rsquo;m pretty pleased with how it looks. I&rsquo;m also happy to find that its USB cable is long enough to reach around to my tower without having to use an extension. And we&rsquo;re all aware of Apple&rsquo;s spitefully non-compatible USB extension cables.</p>

<h2>The Keys</h2>

<p>This keyboard has much taller keys than the Apple keyboards. I&rsquo;d say 5-6 times the height. This provides a longer keypress &ldquo;travel time&rdquo; and gives the typing center of my brain a chance to get ready to pullback from the keypress. I also like they way that the keys press &ldquo;up&rdquo; against your finger during the entire keystroke. Also, the tops of the keys are concave, which does seem to help me keep my hands in the right position.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/6963468995/" title="Tactile Pro 3 by Matt Morris, on Flickr"><img class="<a" src="href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7048/6963468995_24d6403a57_z.jpg">http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7048/6963468995_24d6403a57_z.jpg</a>" width="640" height="425" title="&lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 Num Pad&rsquo; &lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 Num Pad&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<h2>Wide-ness</h2>

<p>With the arrow keys set aside from the letter keys and the numpad off to the right, this keyboard is much wider than the Apple wireless keyboard. I don&rsquo;t have to hold my legs and arms so awkwardly together when using it in my lap. The downside to this is that it takes up more real estate on my desk, which is often inhabited by two laptops, two widescreen monitors, and an external hard drive.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/matthewmorris/6963469213/lightbox" title="Tactile Pro 3 vs Apple Wireless Keyboard by Matt Morris, on Flickr"> <img class="<a" src="href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/6963469213_754e0cf975_z.jpg">http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7204/6963469213_754e0cf975_z.jpg</a>" width="640" height="426" title="&lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 vs Apple Wireless Keyboard&rsquo; &lsquo;Tactile Pro 3 vs Apple Wireless Keyboard&rsquo;" ></a></p>

<h2>Clickety Clickety Clack!</h2>

<p>The Tactile Pro 3 is, if nothing else, loud. A keypress makes several distinct sounds as you press. I like this because it&rsquo;s more signaling that my brain can use in determining the right moment to release a key and move on.  I find that I am able to do a softer keypress even when I&rsquo;m typing at full speed. But more than that, it&rsquo;s just really really fun to work on a clicky keyboard.  Maybe this is just nostalga for the Apple II or Apple Extended.</p>

<p>The big potential downside of the loudness is that it might be distracting to your office mate, or even to coworkers several dozen meters down the hall. This is something that I sometimes worry about, and I&rsquo;m still trying to decide if I should buy my office mate a pair of noice cancelling headphones.
<blockquote><p>I say your colleagues should learn to love your loud keyboard. It&rsquo;s a sign that you&rsquo;re hard at work. &ldquo;Hey Dave&rsquo;s working, listen to Dave&hellip; Holy hell, Dave&rsquo;s getting some shit done, I&rsquo;m gonna get back to work.&rdquo;</p><footer><strong>John Gruber</strong> <cite>The Talk Show #81 <a href="http://5by5.tv/talkshow/81">http://5by5.tv/talkshow/81</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<h2>Other Niceties</h2>

<ul>
<li>Laser Etched Keys (should show less wear than painted)</li>
<li>Symbols and Special Characters are also on the key surface</li>
<li>No limit on the number of simultaneous keystrokes</li>
</ul>


<h2>Negatives?</h2>

<p>There are a few keys at the edge of the keyboard which sometimes exhibit additional friction while the key is being pressed down. I suspect that it&rsquo;s because my hand is far from the key, and as a result my finger is not striking the key at an angle perpendicular to the keyboard&rsquo;s back plane. I&rsquo;m exerting some force to the side, and it&rsquo;s causing the key to rub against the housing a little. But this doesn&rsquo;t bother me too often, and maybe with some practice I can develop the muscle memory to avoid it completely.</p>

<p>Lastly, the frame isn&rsquo;t quite as solid and heavy as I would consider ideal. If you&rsquo;re keyboard isn&rsquo;t the first thing you grab when a home intruder is kicking down your door, you may have the wrong keyboard.</p>

<h2>Price</h2>

<p>At 150 USD, this isn&rsquo;t a trivial purchase. But if you&rsquo;re a professional that uses a keyboard all day, day and night, all year round, then it&rsquo;s really not that much to spend on the right tools. And even if there&rsquo;s no <strong>real</strong> speed increase with a clicky keyboard, I still feel it&rsquo;s worth it to have tools that aren&rsquo;t a daily annoyance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
