<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: telecommuting | Matt Morris]]></title>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/categories/telecommuting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-18T17:46:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mmorris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working from Home]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2013/07/21/working-from-home/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-21T21:16:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2013/07/21/working-from-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past five years, I have worked in a traditional office. A few weeks ago, I moved a thousand miles across the country and became a telecommuter. Several months before the move, I started gathering material to try to help me prepare for the new work situation. Here are a few I found useful.</p>

<!--more-->


<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.70decibels.com/homework/">Home Work</a> is an excellent podcast examines the ins and outs of telecommuting and freelancing. I&rsquo;m not a freelancer, so I cherry picked the episodes that seemed most relevant to me. If you&rsquo;re currently an office worker but think you might like to try working from home, check out <a href="http://www.70decibels.com/homework/2012/9/21/027-telecommuting-basics.html">Episode 27 &ndash; Telecommuting Basics</a> and <a href="http://www.70decibels.com/homework/2013/4/19/055-telecommuting.html">Episode 55 &ndash; Telecommuting</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://lifehacker.com/the-beginners-guide-to-working-from-home-733412770">The Beginner&rsquo;s Guide to Working from Home</a> is a recent article that has several good tips for a new home worker.</li>
<li><a href="http://whowritesforyou.com/2013/04/22/working-from-home/">Working From Home</a> covers many of the pitfalls and challenges associated with working from home, and offers several tips on how to make it work.</li>
</ul>


<p>Here&rsquo;s my core advice to anyone about to start telecommuting for the first time. Give some proactive thought and planning to your home office setup, your work/life schedule and boundaries, and your effectiveness as a communicator. Also, try to be aware of what distractions are most problematic for you and take steps to minimize them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
