<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: self | Matt Morris]]></title>
  <link href="http://mattmorr.is/categories/self/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mattmorr.is/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-28T10:58:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mattmorr.is/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Lieu of Ads]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattmorr.is/2013/04/20/in-lieu-of-ads/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-20T00:11:04-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattmorr.is/2013/04/20/in-lieu-of-ads</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently saw <a href="https://github.com/begriffs/lucre">this project</a> in my news feed and wanted to give it a try. It&rsquo;s a simple rails app that gives you an easy way to accept credit card payments online. I&rsquo;ve never liked the way that ads looked on my site, so I&rsquo;m going to run a &ldquo;tip me&rdquo; button for a while and see how that works.</p>

<p>If you find one of my posts useful, or if you&rsquo;d just like to buy me a coffee, <a href="http://pay-matt.herokuapp.com">give it a try</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 Goals]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattmorr.is/2013/01/01/2013-goals/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T15:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattmorr.is/2013/01/01/2013-goals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here are a few of the goals I&rsquo;ve set for 2013.</p>

<ol>
<li>Post at least one blog entry per week.</li>
<li>Read 12 books: either fiction or nonfiction.</li>
<li>Learn a new technology by building a new app or service. Currently I&rsquo;m thinking of doing something on heroku with Rails.</li>
</ol>


<p>What goals are you setting for 2013?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kid Vids Rejection]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattmorr.is/2012/09/30/kid-vids-rejection/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T14:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattmorr.is/2012/09/30/kid-vids-rejection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after the iPhone 5 announcement, I began updating <a href="http://bit.ly/NeDHS2">Kid Vids</a> for compatibility with the larger screen. Since Kid Vids is a video player, I was especially excited to take advantage of the 16x9 aspect ratio.</p>

<p>To my surprise, this update was rejected due to copyright concerns.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>First I&rsquo;ll explain how this simple app works. Given a YouTube playlist ID, it will play videos from that playlist. That&rsquo;s really it. It doesn&rsquo;t let you browse YouTube and it doesn&rsquo;t offer a way to search for videos. I do this using Google&rsquo;s <a href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/code#ObjectiveC">Objective C Client Library</a>.</p>

<p>The functionality and obvious limitations of this app are completely intentional. I wanted a way to play a selection of hand-picked videos for my kids without the possibility of an inappropriate video appearing as a &ldquo;Related Video.&rdquo; And the introduction of Guided Access in iOS 6 makes it an even better solution to my original problem.</p>

<p>Fast forward to last week. I got a push notification from the iTunes Connect informing me that the submission had been rejected. Strange, I thought, since this was perhaps the 8th update to the app and it had never had a problem before. Once I logged into iTunes Connect, I found this explanation:</p>

<blockquote><p>We found that your app contains features that may infringe on rights owned by Children&rsquo;s Television Workshop, which is not in compliance with the App Store Review Guidelines.</p>

<p>Specifically, we noticed your app contains clips and videos from the Sesame Street television series.</p></blockquote>

<p>But my app bundle does not contain any clips and video whatsoever. It just streams video from YouTube. It does include a few playlist IDs that I offer as a way to get started quickly in the event that the user does not have a YouTube account at the ready. Since this is an app targeted at children, Sesame Street factored heavily into my selection.</p>

<p>The videos that I include are all from <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/SesameStreet">Sesame Street&rsquo;s public YouTube page</a>. You can even play them through Mobile Safari, the <em>new</em> YouTube.app, or any of the other countless iOS applications that include YouTube functionality.</p>

<p>So, rather than to rework all my presets, I decided to submit an appeal to the App Review Board. I don&rsquo;t see a way to get the exact text of my appeal back from the website, but this was the gist of my argument:</p>

<ul>
<li>The Kid Vids app bundle&rsquo;s payload does not contain any video at all.</li>
<li>It only plays (streams) public content from YouTube.</li>
<li>I believe Kid Vids to be fully compliant with the <a href="https://developers.google.com/youtube/terms">YouTube Developer Terms of Service</a>.</li>
<li>The sale of an API client is explicitly permitted in Section 1.2 of these terms.</li>
</ul>


<p>After a few days, I received this friendly, albeit somewhat terse, reply:</p>

<blockquote><p>Thank you for submitting an appeal to the App Review Board for the review of your app, Kid Vids.</p>

<p>We have completed the evaluation of your appeal and have determined that the review findings of 9/19/12 are appropriate.</p>

<p>While this version of your app will not be posted to the App Store, we hope you will consider revising your app to address the issue and bring your into compliance with the Guidelines.</p></blockquote>

<p>I can only imagine that the App Review Board feels it is simply not worth risking litigation by approving an app that <em>seems</em> to violate a copyright. I&rsquo;m sure if I were in their shoes, I would be equally cautious. On the other hand, I wonder how many &ldquo;Wang Ting&rdquo; apps are still available on the App Store. (See this <a href="http://iphonedevelopment.blogspot.com/2012/08/irksome-but-nothing-new.html">article by Jeff Lamarche</a>)</p>

<p>So, I &ldquo;turned off&rdquo; Sesame Street in the app and resubmitted. Not a big deal in the end. Hopefully it goes through this time without a hitch. But what if the reviewer for the next update finds a new supposed violation with some other video? It would be tiresome to have to go through this song and dance for every update submission.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Experience with LASIK]]></title>
    <link href="http://mattmorr.is/2012/07/14/my-experience-with-lasik/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-14T12:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mattmorr.is/2012/07/14/my-experience-with-lasik</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Two months ago, in preparation for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LASIK">LASIK</a> eye surgery, I searched the internet for accounts of people&rsquo;s experiences with the procedure. I found a wide variety of results, most of which were positive. Since I didn&rsquo;t find anything from the point of view of a professional programmer, I will leave my account here.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>The Facts</h2>

<ul>
<li>Pre-surgery, I was highly <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Myopia">myopic</a> with a prescription of -8.75 in both eyes.</li>
<li>Pre-surgery, my vision was correctable to 20/15 (better than 20/20)</li>
<li>Date of surgery: May 30th, 2012 @ 7:30am</li>
<li>Post-surgery prescription, measured the day after surgery:

<ul>
<li>Left Eye:  -0.25</li>
<li>Right Eye: -0.75</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>I&rsquo;m told that &ndash;.25 is effectively 20/20.</p>

<h2>My Daily Routine</h2>

<p>I believe that <strong>how</strong> you use your eyes every day is an important factor to consider when thinking about LASIK. For someone in a career that requires almost constant use of a computer, having clear and reliable vision is very important. To give a clearer picture of my results and whether or not you can draw any conclusions from my impressions, here is a rough outline of my typical day.</p>

<ul>
<li>Awake at 5:45</li>
<li>Leave house by 6:45</li>
<li>40+ minute commute</li>
<li>At work: 8+ hours of programming</li>
<li>Workout during lunch</li>
<li>40+ minute commute</li>
<li>Dinner + family time.</li>
<li>Once kids are asleep: 4+ hours of programming on personal projects.</li>
</ul>


<p>(Note: This is the fullest possible schedule. I can&rsquo;t pull this off every day.)</p>

<p>During the pre-surgery interviews with the surgeon, I explained that I am a professional programmer and asked if I could be expected to return to work the next day. Answer: yes.</p>

<h2>The Surgery</h2>

<p>The surgery itself was not a big deal. It was a little uncomfortable at one point when a suction device is attached to the eye, but that didn&rsquo;t last long. When I first got up from the opterating table, everything appeared as if I were underwater. This was, in fact, because there is actually fluid in the eye that drains away over the next 24-48 hours.</p>

<h2>Recovery, Day 0</h2>

<p>After the surgery, I was driven home by a family member. There was no pain, but my vision was cloudy and I would have been unable to drive. My two boys were at home with a babysitter. Once home, I attempted to close my eyes and rest, at the recommendation of the surgeon.</p>

<p>Later that day there was more discomfort, but my vision was already beginning to clear. I cooked the boys dinner and got them ready for bed with no problem.</p>

<p>Once they were asleep in bed, I sat down at the computer to check my email and maybe try to work on some of my apps. <strong>I was barely able to read email.</strong> Needless to say, I was a little concerned, since I was scheduled to return to work the next day. But I decided not to worry about it for the time being, hoping that 8 hours of sleep would give my eyes time to rest and recover.</p>

<h2>Recovery, Day 1: Halos</h2>

<p>The next day I realized that I was seeing the dreaded &ldquo;halo&rdquo; effect that I had read about online. Around every light source, I saw a very noticeable ring of light. It turns out that this didn&rsquo;t really bother me when I was doing most &ldquo;normal&rdquo; activities. Computer screens, however, turned out to be a problem. They emit light, and when reading text on screen, each character produced its own halo, and every halo overlapped with the ones adjacent to it. This created an unbearable blurring effect that made it very difficult to read on-screen text.</p>

<p>In fact, I went in for a 24 hour followup that day. My prescription was measured using a autorefractor, and my vision was determined to be very close to 20/20. However, I was almost completely unable to read the letters on the eye chart. The eye chart appeared to be an LCD backlit display, and this was producing haloing effects around the letters.</p>

<p>I did manage to get to work that day. However, it was frustrating becuase I had to place the screens mere inches from my face and increase the font in Xcode to rediculous sizes. It was so large that I suspected people could read my code from the hallway by my office.</p>

<h2>Recovery, Week 1</h2>

<p>The halo effect persisted well into the first week. It was still difficult to read a computer screen, but I found that if I used the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000VS1HSA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000VS1HSA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=matmor-20">lubricant eye drops</a> recommended by the doctor, it helped a great deal. Yes, the drops temporarily cleared my vision. I found that if I used the drops every 45 minutes or so, I could code the whole day without getting too frustrated.</p>

<h2>One Month Later</h2>

<p>At times I still have to use the lubricant eye drops in order to use a computer, but my vision has gradually improved to the point that I somteimes go several hours without having to do so.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been asked several times how satisfied I am with the procedure. I think that if I had any type of job that doesn&rsquo;t require reading code on a screen for 10+ hours a day, I would be 99% satisfied. As this is not the case, I would probably say that I am 85% satisfied.</p>

<p>To this date, I still feel that my vision continues to improve. If you&rsquo;ve recently had LASIK and are concerned because your vision is still blurry, your eyes may still be healing. Try not to worry.</p>

<h2>Tips</h2>

<ul>
<li>Close your eyes and rest as much as possible on the first day. I think I tried to do too much that first day and I wonder if it slowed my recovery.</li>
<li>If you experience halos and have trouble reading a computer screen, try the <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000VS1HSA/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=B000VS1HSA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=matmor-20">lubricant eye drops</a>.</li>
<li>Use them frequently, even if the dryness doesn&rsquo;t bother you.</li>
<li><strong>Try to schedule a short vacation from work beginning the day of your surgery. If this is not possible, try to schedule the surgery right before a 3-day weekend.</strong> Reading a computer screen as part of a demanding job was stressful during these first days, but driving, cooking, playing with the kids, etc. was not a problem at all. Drive to the coast and get some rest.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Fun Fact</h2>

<p>Radial Keratotomy, a predecessor to the LASIK procedure, was discovered by accident after a young boy fell off his bycicle and broke his glasses. Some time after the doctor had removed the shards of glass from his eye, his visual acuity had improved. [<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radial_keratotomy#Development">source</a>]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
