<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: twitter | Matt Morris]]></title>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/categories/twitter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-04T15:59:53-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mmorris.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Matt Morris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interception Source Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/08/22/interception-source-code/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-22T21:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/08/22/interception-source-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In light of the recent <a href="https://dev.twitter.com/blog/changes-coming-to-twitter-api">announcement</a> regarding version 1.1 of the Twitter API, it now makes sense why clicking on a Twitter notification in notification center launches Safari. To make sure that they can show us ads when they want to, they&rsquo;re driving as many people as they can to the official Twitter UI.</p>

<p>So, I&rsquo;ve decided to go ahead and push the <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/Interception">code</a> for Interception to github in case anyone wants to enhance it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Notification Center and Native Twitter Clients]]></title>
    <link href="http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/29/notification-center-and-native-twitter-clients/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mmorris.github.io/2012/07/29/notification-center-and-native-twitter-clients</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Late last week, I finally got around to setting up Twitter as an account on Mountain Lion. I was disappointed to see that clicking a Twitter notification launches the default web browser and not Twitter.app or any other client. I do not enjoy using Twitter&rsquo;s web interface, so I wrote a simple application that forwards these clicks to a native Twitter application of your choice.</p>

<!--more-->


<h2>Quick Start</h2>

<p>If this sounds like something that you would find useful, <a href="http://bit.ly/RjnPQz">download the beta</a> and give it a try. The application is a single dialog that asks for your preferred Twitter client. Click &lsquo;Okay&rsquo; and you&rsquo;re all set. There should be no need to run the app again unless you want to switch to a different client.</p>

<center><img src="/downloads/images/interception_ui.png"></center>


<h2>Disclaimer</h2>

<p>This software should be considered very &ldquo;beta.&rdquo; If things get weird and you find you can&rsquo;t open http URLs anymore or something like that, just delete the .app and <a href="http://www.twitter.com/boxel">let me know</a>.</p>

<h2>How It Works</h2>

<p>Interception registers itself as the default handler the URLs that are invoked when you click on a Twitter notification. If it notices a Twitter URL is being loaded by Launch Services, it catches the request and forwards it to the native twitter client you have chosen. All other URLs are silently passed as-is to the default web browser. A previous version of Interception set itself as the default http URL handler for the system, but this is no longer necessary.</p>

<h2>Known Issues and Next Steps</h2>

<p>Interception currently supports only the following Twitter clients:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://tapbots.com/tweetbot_mac/">Tweetbot for Mac</a></li>
<li>Twitter.app</li>
<li>Tweet Deck</li>
<li><a href="http://hibariapp.com">Hibari</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Currently Interception is just hard-coded with the bundle identifiers for each of these apps. In a future version, I might add a &ldquo;Choose App&rdquo; button which would let the user. If your favorite native Twitter client is not one of these four, please let me know.</p>

<p>Also, Twitter mentions and direct messages should land the user on different views inside the targeted Twitter app. I began to wire this up, but it seems that the Tweetbot for Mac public alpha is not yet honoring the <a href="http://tapbots.com/blog/development/tweetbot-url-scheme">Tweetbot URL Scheme</a>, so I put that functionality on hold for all clients. Tweetbot is awesome, and this will be the next feature I add.</p>

<p>I have created a <a href="https://github.com/mmorris/Interception">project</a> over on <a href="https://github.com">Github</a> where I will host the code. I have not posted it yet for two reasons. First, I did this in a bit of a hurry and I would like to clean up the code before I throw it out into the wild. Second, if our local Cocoaheads chapter gets going in the next month or two, I might like to present the project at a meeting and then release the source code and slides all at the same time.</p>

<h2>Wrap-Up</h2>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/RjnPQz">Download It Here</a>. Feedback is welcome.</p>

<p>I realize that if you&rsquo;re favorite Twitter client is in the Mac App Store, it can use push notifications in Mountain Lion, in which case Interception won&rsquo;t really be that useful. I&rsquo;ve really been enoying Tweetbot for Mac, but it&rsquo;s currently in alpha and doesn&rsquo;t yet support remote push notifications. This application grew out of a script I wrote because I wanted to be able to launch Tweetbot from a notification even if Tweetbot wasn&rsquo;t already running.</p>

<p>Incidentally, I&rsquo;ve lost track of how many times I typed &ldquo;Inception&rdquo; while writing this post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
